Look at that!
All right, good. Now stand
to the right of the tree.
All right, around here?
Yeah, get closer to the tree.
A little more to the left.
Around here?
All right, right there. Good.
Come on, let's wrap this up quickly.
What on earth are they doing?
They seem to be peering through something.
What can you see, Mr. Screech Owl?
Oh, I can't see a thing until nightfall.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
Listen, my babies are about to be
born. What if something happens?
I've seen that before.
They're surveying the land.
What do they plan on
doing once it's surveyed?
Beats me!
That really is a massive tree.
You're so right, Boss.
That tree really bothers me.
I know!
♪ Koorogi-ko wa boku no tomodachi. ♪
The little cricket is my friend.
♪ Tottemo suteki na nakayoshi nano sa. ♪
We're the very best of pals.
- Mokkun umai na~
Mokku sure is good at this!
♪ Dakedo dake... ♪
But... bu...
Hey Mokku!
Hey, Giorgio, good morning!
Mokku, could you come here for a second?
No way, I'm heading to school.
I don't have time to dilly-dally.
I know, but it won't take long. Please!
I have to be a good boy if I want
to become human. Don't tempt me.
It's hard enough for me
to stay on track as it is.
Some human adults
gathered around the Oak Tree...
...and they're doing something strange.
What? Around the Oak Tree?
I have a bad feeling something
awful is about to happen.
What on earth are they trying to do?
Please, go find out what's going on.
I can't understand human speech.
You say you've got a bad feeling?
All right, I'll go.
Thanks, Mokku. Let's go!
All right!
Mokku...
Mokku is actually trying to do
something to help Giorgio today.
Well, I won't scold him for straying this
time. Let's just see how this plays out.
Huh? Aren't they just surveying the land?
The one setting up the
pole is Franco's papa.
I know that.
You want to know what on
earth they're doing that for, right?
Got it. I'll go ask for you.
Franco's papa, good morning!
Franco's papa!
What?
Oh, it's Mokku.
What are you measuring this place for?
What's this?
Hey! What are you peeking at?!
This isn't for kids to see!
Fix my neck, my neck!
Boss, shall we head down the mountain soon?
That was awful...
Huh, they left.
Hey, Mokku. Did you find out?
No, no good.
And you were our only hope.
Aw, don't look so sad.
I know, I'll ask Franco. All right?
Is that true, Franco?
Yeah, it's true.
I heard Papa talking to
Mama about it last night.
It's gonna be great once
the amusement park is built!
But Franco, what on earth
is an amusement park?
It's a playground for kids like us.
They're building an amusement
park with all kinds of rides.
It's gonna be amazing!
It's a kids' paradise, with a carousel,
a Ferris wheel, and tons of rides!
Wow, that sounds
like it'll be a lot of fun.
Come on, you'll get to play
there every day, so you must
be looking forward to it, too.
Yeah, I hope it's finished soon.
Hey, Franco, tell your papa
to hurry up and build it!
Sure, will do. I'll tell him.
Franco's papa is really amazing.
You bet he is!
Huh? An amusement park here?
It's the quietest place in
the village, with the best view.
They say they're building a huge
one, with tons of things to play on.
But this Oak Tree will be
all right, won't it, Mokku?
That's right. They wouldn't
cut it down, would they?
Well... I didn't ask about that.
What if it gets chopped down?
What will we do? We
won't have anywhere to live!
Mokku, that's not going to happen, right?
D-Don't ask me. It's not
like I'm the one building it.
Mokku, this affects you, too!
It's useless if you don't ask the most
important thing! Hurry up and find out!
B-But...
Just go! If you dawdle, I'll
poke your butt like last time!
A-All right, I get it!
Mokku, hurry up, hurry!
Quit dragging your feet!
I'm going, I'm going!
We're counting on you, Mokku!
I wonder if Mokku will be okay.
He doesn't seem very reliable.
Man, that scared me. Why
does everyone get so worked up?
Ugh, I got dirt in my mouth. Geez.
Why do I have to rush around
like this? Give me a break.
Oh no, look what I did.
It has nothing to do with me anyway.
Whether that Oak Tree gets chopped
down or whatever happens to it...
...it's not my problem.
You idiot!
You ungrateful brat!
That Oak Tree is your mother!
My mother?
Listen to me!
The Fairy who gave you life
lives in that Oak Tree! You big fool!
The Fairy who gave me life...
Mokku, I am the Fairy of
the Oak Tree, your home.
I have heard Grandfather's wish,
and I have come to give you life.
Grant life to the wooden puppet, Mokku.
And Mokku, do you remember...
...when you fell into this stream...
...and were almost smashed
to pieces in the waterfall basin...
Who was it that reached
out a hand to save you?
Help me!
Hang in there, Mokku!
Mokku, hold on!
Be brave!
If you give up over something like
this, you can never become human.
Now, take heart and climb out.
Do you really not care if that
Oak Tree gets chopped down?
I'll ask Franco's papa to see if they're
really going to cut down the Oak Tree.
That's it, that's the spirit!
I'm counting on you, Mokku.
Hey, wait up. I'm coming too.
Cheers!
To celebrate the President's new project...
I made a success of the
coastal tourism business.
This time, I'll make sure that mountain
amusement park succeeds without fail!
Once it's built, huge
crowds will be packing in!
Which means money will come rolling in...
Yes, I'll do anything for money!
I have to build the amusement
park as soon as possible!
To do that, first we've gotta chop down
that huge oak tree on top of the mountain!
I knew it...
Mokku! They really are going
to cut down the Oak Tree!
Are you just going to let them, Mokku?!
The Oak Tree... The Oak Tree
is going to be cut down...
Stop!
Help!
Stop! Stop!
Please stop!
Mokku, help me!
Stop it! Please stop!
A dream...? Thank goodness
it was just a dream...
All right! I'll definitely
protect that Oak Tree!
♪ Ore wa kono mura no nanushi ♪
I'm the headman of this village—
♪ Shiruku Hato ni mo ♪
...and to think even Silk Hat...
♪ nigete kuru ka to. ♪
...comes running to me!
♪ Etto ♪
Uh, so...
♪ ojiji-sama no okaeri da to. ♪
...the old master's coming home, is he?
Franco's papa!
Who is it?
Sorry...
There are two or three of you.
What is it? What do you want?
Is it true they're building an amusement
park on the Oak Tree's mountain?
Yeah, that's right. And it's
going to be something incredible.
Could you please stop?
Huh? Yeah, sure, like I'd stop!
Wh-What?
That Oak Tree on my hill...
I mean, all kinds of animals
and insects live in that tree.
So please, can't you
leave it the way it is?
Stop messing around!
What kind of nonsense
are you talking? Shut up!
Give your stupidity a rest!
Please. Stop it.
Shut up!
Please, listen to me! I'm begging you!
Like hell we'll listen to that!
Ah! Mokku!
Oh, that's terrible.
Mokku, are you all right?
Spouting such nonsense.
Come on, Mokku, pull yourself together!
Oh, no, I can't go to school like this.
What a cruel thing to do.
Now, if you've learned your
lesson, hurry up and go home.
Giorgio!
Eh! Hey!
Hey! Give my hat back!
You little prankster,
get down from there right now!
Serves you right!
Making a fool out of me...
just watch what I'll do!
Ah, a gun!
Oh! So feisty!
How exciting!
Look out Giorgio!
Stop! Stop!
Shut up!
My hand...
It snapped...
Giorgio!
Hang in there!
Serves you right!
Grandpa, Giorgio will be
able to fly again, won't he?
The injury isn't serious. He'll
heal if he rests for a day or two.
That's a relief, Giorgio.
If the Oak Tree is going to be chopped
down, who cares if my wings heal or not.
What are you saying, Giorgio?
Because it's true! Everyone's
home will be gone!
There's no point in living like that.
Now then, Mokku's hand... let's see.
Oh, that's right. I used up
the rest of the oak wood...
...when I fixed Mokku's leg the other day.
Don't worry anymore. I'll
go negotiate with Vittorio.
Really, Grandpa?!
The plateau with that Oak Tree has
the most beautiful view in the village.
I am completely against building some
gaudy playground in a place like that.
The sensible villagers
will surely oppose it too.
We'll all stand together
and protect the Oak Tree.
Please do, Grandpa.
Isn't that great, Giorgio?
Yeah. I want to go tell the
squirrels and wild birds right away.
Mokku, look, your arm is all finished.
Being a wooden puppet makes you easy
to repair, thankfully. There, how's that?
Thank you, Grandpa.
Huh, that's weird.
What's wrong with it?
Hm? What's the matter?
Grandpa, it won't move like it used to.
It isn't from the Oak Tree, so it
probably won't move right away.
Don't worry, it'll move
once you get used to it.
Well, I have to go talk to him.
I wonder...
What the hell are you babbling about?
An old geezer like you
has no business interfering!
Vittorio, please. This is a peaceful
mountain. I want you to leave it in peace.
The mountain is far more beautiful as
it is than with some amusement park.
You just stick to your
woodcarving, old man!
Building an amusement park there
is already a done deal. Now get lost!
No matter how much you object,
it won't change a thing, old man!
B-But, Vittorio!
Goodbye!
Then there's really no
saving the Oak Tree...
Forgive me, it's all
because I'm so powerless.
Let us pray to God to
protect the Oak Tree...
That's the only thing we can do right now.
God, please protect the Oak
Tree. Please hear Mokku's prayer.
Hurry up and get ready!
Do you have all the tools?
Yes!
All right, let's begin! Cut that tree down!
Ah, at last...
...our final moment come...
All right, let's do this...
Hey!
Ah! It's Mokku!
Stop it! Stop cutting down the Oak Tree!
This is none of your business!
Stop! Please, I'm begging you!
Get lost!
Keep getting in our way and
I'll smash you to pieces first!
Hey! Wait! Stop! I beg of you!
Listen here, old man! Get in our
way again and you won't be spared!
That's right, I have official
permission from the town hall!
Grandpa, if they cut down
the Oak Tree, I'd rather die!
All right, boys, get to it!
Mokku, what are you saying?
But Grandpa, Mama... the Oak
Tree is going to be cut down!
Mokku, pray. Pray to God.
What are you muttering...?
God! Please! Please save the Oak Tree!
Please save the Oak Tree... Save my mother!
I beg you! Take my life instead!
Please... Please save my mother!
God!
All right, let's do this!
Divine punishment from the oak tree!
The oak tree is cursed!
Help!
Forget it!
Run!
Help!
Grandpa!
Mokku!
Help me!
Somebody help me!
Vittorio, take my hand!
Grandpa, you shouldn't help a guy like him!
Fool!
Come on, grab on, Vittorio!
I-I'm sorry...
Hold on, Mokku. Almost there.
Thank you, Mokku. Thank you.
I'm sorry. Please forgive me.
You did well, Mokku.
Everything is all right now.
Thank goodness! I'm so glad!
It's all thanks to Mokku!
Mokku, you did so well
protecting the Oak Tree.
Thank you. And you did well to
help others with that disabled hand.
I will give you a reward.
I shall transfer the life of the oak
branch struck by lightning into this hand.
Ah! It moves! It's moving!
Grandpa! Grandpa! I-I-It's
fixed! My left hand can move!
Is that so? That's wonderful!
The Fairy was right after
all! It moves, Grandpa!
Because you tried so hard to protect
the Oak Tree, God healed it for you.
If only you were always a good boy like
this, I wouldn't have such a hard time.
Mokku is gradually becoming a good boy.
Learning that Mokku is at his wit's
end after insects ate one of his legs...
Kenken and his gang
hatch another evil scheme.
In exchange for telling
him who can fix his leg...
...they tell him to break the embankment.
Suspecting nothing, Mokku is tricked
into throwing stones at the embankment.
And that night, heavy
rain begins to fall...
...and an overflowing torrent of water
violently assaults the embankment.
Look forward to next week's
Kashi no Ki Mokku!